[Music]
hi and welcome to this session on what's
new in financial management it's an
overview session of the features and
improvements we've done to financial
management in business Central in
this uh
2024 wave one Rel my name is Brian nson
I'm a program manager with the business
Central team and I'll take you through
the
features we made quite a few
improvements some of these improvements
uh have their own videos we have done GL
revaluation or currency code on G
general ledger
entries uh We've added some Excel
reports more to come we've done uh
improvements to consolidation and we
have focused on collection management
where we have created a new role Center
and improved the reminder process all of
these
capabilities have their own
video so I won't go into much detail
here and then we have uh allowing zero
lines in recurring journals with the fix
method nice little Improvement and we
have also enabled currency posting to
employee lers that we introduced a few
releases ago so let's just take take a a
brief look at each of these features so
you know where to find them and and what
they will do for you but for the top
ones uh go and find the video that digs
a little deeper into these topics so GL
revaluation has been the top idea on the
BC idea site for a long time in the GL
account card you will now be able to
specify when you're posting a journal or
a doc ment um with currency whether you
will accept for this DL account that
currencies are posted with the same
currency which you will then specify
maybe you just want um transactions in
one currency it could be that you will
only allow local currency and you don't
want any currency transactions to it
it's also an option uh you may want
multiple
currencies uh or in this case uh I'm I'm
about to select blank here you will
allow any currency you will also be able
to set a small toggle whether you want
revaluation to happen for for this
account and you can also decide whether
that adjustment or reevaluation entry
will go to unrealized or realized uh
adjustment
accounts so if you decide that you will
accept multiple
currencies um there's a small uh
Associated table with the GL account
where you can specify which accounts oh
sorry which currencies are allowed when
you post currency
transactions and finally once you've
done it there is a badge job in the CH
of accounts where you can execute um an
adjustment badge job that will then
create adjustment entries that you can
post and because it's a journal with
some entries you can go in and and
adjust them and validate them before you
post we have added uh a set of excel
reports in this uh major release that
comes out here in April there are eight
new reports they are uh suffixed with a
preview tag because we expect to make
changes to them and small
improvements um in this first release
there are eight uh I know that we are
working on the next 12 uh reports and
the complete list is somewhere between
25 and 30 depending on
on how you see
it uh the new reports like the the ones
that are in here now are trial balances
like your on general ledger and we have
some AIDS receivables AIDS payables and
a top list for customers and vendors one
of the reports uh could look like this
this is the8
receivables Excel
reports uh can manage a lot of data but
there are still some restriction and
limitations so we have uh in in the
first batch of reports focused on the
reports that still makes a lot of sense
uh looking at in Excel even though
they're
aggregated um most of these reports will
have one or multiple uh report Pages we
call them that like in this case there's
a report where you have eight
receivables by period in local currency
in the functional
currency um and sometimes one or or two
EXT pivots on on data if it makes uh
sense in in the in the given report the
underlying data is in um a separate
table so that if you want to create your
own reports you can just refer to this
and start creating your own uh report
maybe you want it by period maybe you
want it to to break it down by customer
group or something else uh you can do
that because the underlying data is
there compared to a normal report from
business Central but it is still
aggregated data and if you want to uh to
dig deeper you will have to wait to one
of the minor releases where some of the
reports will contain more detailed uh
data uh you will have general ledger
entries in the detailed trial balance uh
the accounts receivables I know um you
will probably want to look at at
customer L entries they will come with
the customer balance to date
report uh and similarly for for other
reports so you'll get your details but
remember it is it is Excel it's not a
full copy of the
database um so there are use cases where
this is more relevant to use another
Improvement is the uh consolidation
feature we have helped the user manage
uh currencies when you're doing
consolidations we have enabled the user
to while they're in the process of doing
consolation to look up the currency
exchange rate and if they're trying to
recover from a mistake they can also
look up previous runs and and pick rates
from there um that is an important
aspect of of recovery from or rerunning
previous periods in consolation and
you'll be able to get a better overview
of currencies while you're doing
consolidation another theme in this
release for finance is collection
management or account
receivables um the process of sending
out payment request uh applying payments
uh to outstanding invoices and keep
tracking of your account receivables is
um something that consumes a lot of
resources and time in the finance
department so we decided to focus a
little more on on this in this release
and the coming releases you'll see some
more um to make it um a better process
and for the user to get better
overviews so we started with a new role
center for the account receivables
administrator that gives you the
navigation to the places you want to go
to and the task you want to execute
while you're doing accountables uh the
role Center has some cues so you can
keep track of what's going on in your
business what are the outstanding
invoices the balance and so
forth we've also improved the
reminder um or sending out uh reminders
process uh We've improved how you set up
the terms especially around tailoring uh
the email
text um when you're sending out
reminders because maybe you want to
tailor them to uh to the first email
that you sent out versus the last email
you sent out to ask for for
payments uh but that is all good you get
better overview you get a better uh
setup but we also decided that maybe
it's time that we also help you with the
the full process so we added automation
for reminders and that will help you
create issue and sending out reminders
so you basically don't have to do
anything other than setting it up and
follow along and of course from time to
time pick up the phone and talk to
customers but it has its separate video
where where we go deeper in in this
feature we've also added the
ability to keep zero lines in general
journal General recurring
journals journals in in general we don't
like to post zero to Jour ledger so so
we block you and and throw up a warning
asking you to get either add uh an
amount or get rid of the line that is
causing the error this is all good when
you're posting journals but in recurring
journals uh where you maybe posting acrs
that are the same from from period to
period you want to keep the line because
you want to go and modify each of
them uh in each one and here I'm
referring to when you're using the fixed
uh method like where you set the amount
it could be payroll it could be acels it
could be something else Revenue
recognition and you have a set of lines
that you want to keep track of sometimes
the amount for a given period is
zero uh and normally it would cause an
error but now when you post we will just
keep the line it will it won't be posted
as a zero line it will it will just be
ignored just as when you're doing the
balance
methods
and lastly but not least um we
introduced um employee ledgers um a few
years back uh at that time we focused uh
on local currency because we thought if
you have employees you will reimburse
them in local currency so you when you
type in something you may want to
converted to local currency and but but
you still only need the local currency
amount
but a lot of feedback has been uh sent
our way asking us to enable to
post to with currencies in employee
ledes just just as you would for
customers and vendors and also to keep
track of it and also to adjust balances
if that's the
case so we now allow you to not only
select currency for employees but you
will also see it uh in the general ler
so you can uh look it up for example if
you want to validate something take a
look at uh these new Eight Features we
have in financial management or take a
look at the videos for some of them
where we dig a little deeper in how they
work and where you uh start the the
different features if you have uh ideas
go to for example BC ideas create a new
idea or vote for for any of the existing
ones and provide us with some input for
improving or maybe new features uh we go
through each one of them uh for example
the GL revaluation or currency code on
GL uh is from BC ideas the uh currency
code uh with employee ledgers is also
from from ideas so we do listen so do go
in and give us feedback thank you for
joining this
session